The winner is...
T.M. Opera O has won the Satsuki Sho!
That was... pathetic.
My poor physical condition leading up to the race...
left me unable to run at full strength.
I worked so hard only for it to come to that...
What am I even doing?
I can't let that ever happen again.
I'll show everyone...
I'll show them... at the Japanese Derby...
Onee-chan, I'm going to win it for you.
Hashiridashita hitomi ga
Eyes that being to run,
mezasuno wa ichiban shika nai
aspiring to nothing more than number one
Glorious one moment
shouri de shika tsukamenai kiseki
a miracle that can only achieve victory
Umamusume: Pretty Derby
Road to the Top
Onaji toki wo irodotte
Coloring the very moment,
kagayaki tachi ga jibun wo miteru kara
because the bright lights are looking at me.
Genkai nante kimerarenai
I can't set limits,
unmei ga raibaru
destiny is my rival
Believe Dream
Akogare wa mou chousen ni nattanda
My longing has already become a challenge
Believe Pride
Butai ni tatsun da tte tsuyoi kanjou
I have a strong feeling that I'll be on the stage
Believe Yell
Kotaetai kimochi mo dakishime
Embracing the feeling of wanting to respond
Ima mirai e geeto ga hiraiteku
Now the door of the future opens,
reesu ga hajimatteku
the race begins
Issei taafu ni fuku kaze ni kawaru
It will become the wind blowing on the grass at once
mune no oku no atsui omoi wa
The passion in my heart,
dare ni mo yuzure wa shinai kara
I won't let anyone take it away from me.
Kakenuketeku sokudo wa
The speed at
watashi tachi no sakebi nanda
which we run is our cry
Kisoiau hodo ni hibiiteku
The more we race, the more it resonates
Running to the top!
Eikou to iu gooru e to mukau kiseki
The miracle of running towards the goal of glory
We're left with just one more day to go
until the Japanese Derby!
Episode 2: A Glorious Stage
Who can we expect to take the crown in a race that every Umamusume dreams of entering?
The victorious are nothing less than champions of a generation!
Everyone expected the Satsuki Sho to simply be a one-on-one race to the finish between Narita Top Road and Admire Vega,
but then we saw T.M. Opera O swoop in to win it all.
It's gotta be T.M. Opera O again.
Did you see that Satsuki Sho performance?
Yeah, but Nakayama Racecourse and
Tokyo Racecourse are just too different.
Top Road's gonna have all the time in the world on Tokyo's straightaways to build up some blazin' speed.
I just know that it's going to be Opera O!
No! Ayabe's going to zip right on past everyone at the end!
Top Road is definitely going to take it this time!
Paces are average across the board. The pitch gradually increases as—
I kind of got caught up in a panic here
since I was blocked in.
My mind went totally blank for a moment...
If only I had been a bit more aggressive in coming up with a strategy...
Looks like some of that clumsiness crept out.
The turf was pretty damp due to the rain right before the race.
Nakayama also has those small turns that give
someone like you with a big stride quite the challenge.
Chalking it up to all of that, you simply weren't able to run like you're used to.
Right...
So given the right conditions to
allow you to run at your fullest potential,
you'd be absolutely second to none.
I don't believe that the training
we've done jilts us in the slightest.
The upcoming race presents a golden opportunity to run
like you are used to.
Now you just have to focus on honing those strengths of yours.
A golden opportunity?
Yes!
Hey, Prez!
Good luck at the Derby!
You'll definitely be seeing us in the stands!
I will! Thank you so much!
Come on now, don't pile on the pressure...
No, it's all right.
I'm going to earn you
the title of Derby Trainer for sure!
Man... she's somethin' else.
This staircase is akin to the
Grand Staircase at Palais Garnier itself!
At last, I will be stepping up onto
the very stage of dreams, the Derby!
Behold!
Apollo himself prepares to descend
from the skies in honor of my victory!
I'd expect... no less... from you, Opera O-san.
Just look at... you go!
Opera O!
Eek!
Thank you, my dear scribes.
I would like to make the rounds one last time.
Would you mind waiting for my return?
Of course! Please grace us with
an interview once you've finished!
The reporters just keep on increasing, huh?
They can't ignore my blinding aura
since my victory at the Satsuki Sho.
I would be crowned the one and only
Overlord of this generation of runners...
This is a story too tantalizing to resist.
I-if it were me, I'd just shy away because of all the cameras...
You'd best get used to it now.
I know that
you, too will one day come to bask in the
passionate anticipation and delight of the audience.
Then, let us depart for one more round, Doto!
To the summit of glory we run!
M-Me too?
One day...
Ayabe-san, if you haven't gone to
dinner yet, would you like to go with—
Staying out tonight.
I have permission from the dorm head.
I see...
Tonight is the night of a new moon.
It's strange. On nights of the new moon...
I can feel her presence close.
Of my dearest unborn sister.
Go! Keep it up!
Ever since I was little, and every time I ran...
That joy and excitement one naturally experiences...
would quickly turn to
feelings of acute sadness after.
That sadness was so unlike the usual me.
It's as if the feelings of another well up from within me.
What's wrong, dear?
Later, I was told everything.
That I actually had a twin sister.
And that...
before we were born, it was determined that only one of us could survive.
That one ended up being me...
So it was at that time that I came to realize...
That those feelings of another...
I would experience...
They were those of my sister
who sacrificed herself for me.
It was only by mere chance that I was the one to live on.
The only thing...
I can do now is run for her sake... for my sister,
who's unable to do so on...
her own two feet.
I'm so sorry.
I'm sorry for that pathetic display.
Next time, I won't lose.
Do you know of the Japanese Derby?
The Umamusume who wins...
is considered to stand at
the apex of a generation.
This time...
I'm going to outrun both Top Road and Opera O.
That Opera O... She's quite peculiar.
She has a flair for the dramatic and is ridiculously confident.
You could even say that
she gets under my skin a bit.
Still, I can't underestimate her.
Top Road possesses great ability,
and is always pushing herself further.
She even sees me as an ideal to aspire toward.
Telling someone something like that...
Most would feel pretty embarrassed, wouldn't they? But not her.
She has a certain dazzle.
Though it's one that
I don't want to be outshone by.
Onee-chan!
You loved running so, so much.
I'm so sorry... Because of me... I'm sorry.
I am going to make your dreams come true.
I'm going to win the Derby,
and dedicate the title of strongest Umamusume to you.
Please watch.
Oh, energetic as always, I see!
Give it your best shot at the Derby!
You just gotta win!
Good luck, Top Road-san!
Keep it up, Top Road!
Thank you so much!
I'll be there to cheer you on!
We know you can do it!
Can't wait to see it!
Huh?
Rare to see you leave anything on your plate, Top Road-san.
Have you no appetite?
Or perhaps... are you feeling ill?
Oh, no!
It's just that...
I kind of have a lot on my mind...
Oh yeah, this is great! So yummy!
You're under a lot of pressure, aren't you?
It's like you can't even avoid being reminded of the Derby these days.
You're always working
so hard though, Top Road-san.
I know you'll be fine!
Thank you!
Um, Top Road-senpai?
We all pitched in to get these charms for you.
Please, take them, Senpai!
Wow, thank you so much!
We all aspire to run just like you someday.
Please give it your all at the Derby!
We know that you'll be the champ, Senpai!
You're right. I'm not going to lose.
The Japanese Derby...
A turf race at 2,400 meters.
Tokyo Racecourse features long straightaways.
That should allow her to
maintain her speeds quite well.
All of the conditions are in play to let her freely stretch those legs.
Conscientiously, reliably, flawlessly... I need to give it my best.
Trainer-san and I have worked
tirelessly to perfect this run of mine.
I know... I can do this!
You're out here quite late.
Thank you.
You as well. Have you been
training this whole time?
Yes.
I want nothing more than to win the Japanese Derby.
The Satsuki Sho was so crushing, you know?
Indeed.
Running with you is going to make this the race of a lifetime.
I'm going to be giving my all to this race.
Let's both run without any regrets!
I...
Ah, I knew that you would both be out here,
Top Road-san. Ayabe-san.
On this illustrious evening
before our performance,
I cannot help but feel restless.
I have come to deliver a
proclamation unto both of you.
A proclamation?
I came to realize it a midst
our battle at the Satsuki Sho.
You stand before me as rivals in my path toward becoming Overlord of the future.
Rivals?
Us?
The Japanese Derby approaches!
I shall show you exactly what I am capable of...
at this once-in-a-lifetime production.
I pray that both of you will do the same!
Thank you for letting us know.
But I won't lose!
I shan't have it any other way!
A passionate contest awaits!
Yes!
What about you, Ayabe-san?
Let us chase the joy of victory together!
Let's give it our all!
This has nothing to do with me.
Ayabe-san...
I have my own goal to focus on.
Just... leave me be.
Let me be.
The day has finally come!
The Classic race in which bright-eyed Umamusume seek to ascend to the pinnacle of a generation!
The Japanese Derby!
This year is on the battle between three contenders in particular.
That's right. T.M. Opera O, Admire Vega,
and Narita Top Road.
Any one of them could easily emerge victorious.
You lack nothing compared to anyone else out there. All that remains is putting your best foot forward.
I will.
I'm going to keep my promise.
All right.
Here comes the winner of
the Satsuki Sho, T.M. Opera O.
Can she win the Derby and go on
to be a Triple Crown Umamusume?
Next up is Admire Vega, who regrettably placed sixth at the Satsuki Sho.
She's no doubt poised to win the Derby, and is today's second-favorite to do so.
And now for our third-place finisher at the Satsuki Sho.
Seeking a grand comeback is Narita Top Road, today's favorite to win!
High expectations ride on her shoulders!
The Umamusume are making their way to the starting gate.
Alas, my rivals! Hear you the thunderous applause?
They are cheers in our honor!
The moment of jubilation is forthwith!
Our very dreams are at stake.
Let us give it our all, and make this the greatest of performances!
The race has started!
Number 16, Nautical Tool, is off to a slow start.
Everyone else is running mostly in-line.
T.M. Opera O is running with the pack.
Narita Top Road follows closely behind.
Opera O makes a good mark.
Just be sure to keep up with her, Top Road.
Top Road-san, fight on!
Opera O-san, you can do it!
Admire Vega makes the bold decision to keep up the rear.
She's running third to last.
Paces are average across the board.
Each runner has a distinct placement. How will they proceed from here?
Narita Top Road continues to chase after T.M. Opera O and the pack.
The runners are emerging from
the third turn and into the fourth.
The trailing Umamusume are closing the gap!
Narita Top Road and T.M. Opera O make the turn from the far edge!
Time now to sound the victory hymn!
She's fast! Very fast! T.M. Opera O emerges from the turn at incredible speed!
Narita Top Road chases close behind!
Can T.M. Opera O push to the lead?
Admire Vega also emerges from the outside!
All that remains is the homestretch!
T.M. Opera O! And from the outside,
Narita Top Road! It's T.M. Opera O and Narita Top Road!
I won't let you!
I'm going to win this!
Everything has led to this moment!
This time... for sure!
What's this? Running on the outside, Admire Vega! Admire Vega is pushing fast!
200 meters to go!
Ayabe-san!
I need to win...
I want to win... against those two!
I've got this!
For Trainer-san, for everything he's done for me!
For everyone who has always cheered me on!
I'm going to believe!
Believe in my run!
From the center advances Narita Top Road!
Narita Top Road takes the lead!
Yes!
Push, push!
Keep it up, don't let up!
From the outside comes Admire!
From the outside comes Admire Vega!
I can do it!
Ayabe-san!
Narita Top Road! Admire Vega!
T.M. Opera O in third,
then it's Narita Top Road and Admire Vega!
They're neck and neck!
The supreme victory of the Japanese Derby lies in their sights!
Narita Top Road, Admire Vega!
Narita Top Road!
Go!
Admire Vega! Admire Vega has won!
Casting aside her loss at the Satsuki Sho,
Admire Vega has become a first-class shining star!
I won...
I...
Congratulations!
My running was flawless.
I gave it my absolute all.
But...
Everyone was expecting so much of me...
Trainer-san had placed all of his faith in me...
I couldn't win...
I felt your resolve.
You did good, kid.